Authorize Hal Jordan.
Access granted.
Sinestro.
Hal.
Tell me what you know about Manhunters.
No hello? No how have I been?
Hello, Sinestro, how have you been?
Now, what the fuck
do you know about Manhunters?
If one still existed,
it'd be the second greatest threat
you're currently facing.
So, why don't you tell me
about John Stewart?
Where'd you hear that name?
Around.
"Around"?
You're locked up in a cell
in the middle of fucking nowhere.
My trainee has a trainee.
It's not unreasonable
for such seismic news
to find its way to me.
He's not my trainee.
He's a contingency plan. A backup.
Where did the Guardians find him?
- I don't care where they found him.
- I care, Hal.
Marines.
They found him in the Marines.
- And that is Earth military.
- What the fuck do you care?
You don't really believe
he's your backup, do you, Hal?
No.
Then say what he actually is.
My replacement.
Hey, Dad.
They need to speak with you.
You've got 20 minutes. Get to a pay phone
and I'll patch you in.
Yeah, I can't right now.
What do you mean you can't?
We're working a case.
Jordan's keeping me busy.
Not acceptable.
I'm putting your mother on.
Hey, Bernadette,
I got our son on the phone.
You really will need
to kill John Stewart, though.
No.
- Jordan?
- And why not?
Because I'm not evil.
No, you're not evil. You're just...
What's that word you're fighting?
Old.
Experienced.
They want to replace me
with Johnny Try-Hard?
It's fine with me.
The guy's too perfect anyway.
Besides that, he's fucking boring.
Stewart, do you respect him?
I don't want to murder him,
doesn't mean I like him.
I didn't say like. I said respect.
Well...
It's obvious you don't know
anything about Manhunters,
so enjoy your solitary fucks.
Is one still alive? On Earth?
What do you know?
Manhunters are believed to be extinct.
I know other things about them too.
Unique aspects of their physiology
that cannot be changed
when they take a new form.
If one were alive on your planet,
that information would be
of great interest to the Guardians.
Deliver the Manhunter to the Guardians
and disgrace Stewart in the process.
Tell me, does he speak
to the Guardians directly?
- He says he doesn't.
- And you believed him?
He found out about the Manhunter,
he could've kept it to himself.
All he does is follow orders.
Well, then he can be controlled.
Make him believe
that you're embracing his worthiness
as your replacement.
- Is he fearless?
- He may be.
Then he will be arrogant,
overly confident,
thus blindly oblivious
to your true intent.
Is that how you fooled me?
I was never anything but myself.
My ambition was always a threat.
You simply chose not to see it.
Do not make the same mistake
with John Stewart.
God damn.
It's that big, green asshole's sidekick.
Hey. Uh, I need a scope.
A Schmidt & Bender,
but I'll take a Leupold
or whatever scope
y'all sell with the McMillan.
Can't sell you a scope without a gun.
Oh, no, I don't want the gun.
Well, then you're shit out of luck.
It's a package deal.
Kind of like you and your boss.
Where is he, anyway?
Okay, I'll, uh, I'll get a rifle
and a scope, please.
Thank you.
Let me guess, if I want the tomato,
I gotta get the ham too?
All right, thank you.
Hey.
Y'all were a blast.
Oh, come on, man.
Any sign of our mysterious benefactor?
You can just call him a Manhunter.
It sounds less stupid.
You think he's coming in on that chopper.
That's why you're up here.
See if he lands on that ranch, huh?
Couldn't see who's on board.
Would've been nice
if you were here since you can fly.
Knocked on your door,
- you weren't there.
- I was getting laid in space.
Were you worried about me, Junior?
I was concerned about the alien hit squad
that's gonna find us
in 36 hours if we don't deliver.
So what'd you learn up here, anyway?
The four guard towers on the ranch
- share the same line of sight.
- Which means what?
Well, I think it means
that there's a hidden structure
on the compound.
One that is obscured
from every vantage point,
except those guard towers,
and that's exactly where
that chopper just landed.
That building is a weenie.
- What'd you say?
- It's a...
It's an architectural term
that Walt Disney made up
for structures on his property.
Think Sleeping Beauty's castle
at Disneyland.
Wait, wait, wait.
- You've been to Disneyland?
- No, of course not.
They didn't let me in.
It's the happiest place on Earth,
but they... they said I'd kill the vibe.
Did you just make a joke?
Look, so Walt Disney
built his parks around the weenie,
and I'm thinking
that Macon's done the same thing
- on his compound.
- So you think the Manhunter's
- inside Macon's weenie?
- Maybe.
I mean, the chopper's easy to track.
It lands the same time every day at 9:17.
No pilot would do that every day
unless it was on purpose.
It could be a decoy.
If it is a decoy, then maybe
the Manhunter's not even on the compound.
Just gotta get inside to find out.
First, we gotta find Sheriff Kane.
I gave her my word
that we'd keep her looped in.
Sheriff Kane? Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm, what?
She's married.
And unlike you,
I respect the matrimonial bond.
I believe you.
Let's go. I'll fly us over.
How's that gonna work?
Well, I can either carry you like a baby,
or you can hop on
and pretend like I'm a horse.
Nah, I'm good.
So, this is your jurisdiction too, huh?
My husband owns the bar, so yeah.
Thought he was a lawyer.
Everybody in Rushville multi-tasks.
Okay.
Why don't you go with this one?
Really? How much you want me to say?
- Tell her all of it.
- Okay.
Um, so there's
an interplanetary war criminal
hiding here in Rushville.
The technical term is a Manhunter.
Sorry.
Manhunter?
Really?
You remember those--
our buddies at the game.
Well, the one at the station,
he wasn't the last one.
Apparently there's a crew
of 'em here to assassinate the...
well, the thing that John just mentioned.
Show her the phone.
So one of them gave me this.
They said to call if we find the target.
If we don't find it by tomorrow night,
these aliens are going to waltz into town
and they're gonna blow up.
So what does this thing want?
We don't know, but it's been here a while.
How is that possible?
Well, they can take any form.
It could be anyone
hiding here in Rushville.
So, line everyone up,
put them through those alien detectors.
Well, we can't do that.
Manhunters aren't alien.
They're something else.
Great.
So everybody's a threat
and we're all in danger?
If it could be anyone, why not me?
A long time ago,
a Lantern by the name
of Abin Sur crashed here.
We don't know why,
but there was a Manhunter on board.
Whatever identity that Manhunter took,
well, it wouldn't be
on the records before that.
I... I looked you up.
You are from Gotham and...
it's a very nice senior photo.
I get why you dropped the bangs.
So who's this Manhunter?
I'm sure you have a theory.
We think it's Macon's benefactor.
And because your husband
is Macon's lawyer,
I'm guessing
that you know the moneymaker's identity.
Honestly, I don't.
Come on, you're his wife.
We don't have that kind of relationship.
I've lived here a long time,
and I've never seen Macon's money guy.
How do you two even think
you're gonna get to him?
We think he's in a building on the ranch.
Junior calls it a weenie,
and we're gonna pay a visit to it.
- Okay.
- Okay, that's it?
Aliens are gonna blow up my town.
Finding him will stop them, right?
Right. Probably.
You're only gonna get one shot at this.
Do not miss.
Hey, you think...
Sheriff's gonna tell Macon we're coming?
That would not be good.
- But you don't think she will?
- I do not.
- And that's your gut?
- My gut, always.
Okay, so now what?
We wait.
- For what?
- Nightfall.
Better to burn six hours
than die in broad daylight.
Copy that.
You failed to make contact.
This is disappointing.
I'm sorry.
Jordan's nearby taking a nap.
I was afraid he'd know if I left.
What are you still doing in Nebraska?
We're just cleaning up
from the alien that self-destructed.
Did Jordan tell you
where he traveled last evening?
He said he was having sex in space.
That's a lie.
Okay, where was he?
Violating his oath.
He went to see Sinestro.
What did they talk about?
I was hoping you could tell me.
He doesn't tell me shit.
What's important is that Jordan's actions
have accelerated the inevitable.
I've spoken to the other Guardians.
We're in agreement.
During the course of your training,
- Jordan gives you the ring, yes?
- Yeah.
The moment you put it on your finger,
recite the oath,
and you become
Green Lantern for Sector 2814.
And that's it?
We agreed you would replace him.
Yeah, I just didn't realize
that you were gonna make me do it myself.
I did not realize
that your father's weakness
runs within you.
I was promised by your mother
that that was not the case.
Your mother was wrong.
I doubted at first when she told me
that you were strong,
and that you had integrity,
and that your makeup was sublime
and above most of the others,
that your potential was enormous.
I hesitated,
and I should have
trusted my own instincts.
Jordan has filed multiple reports
about your progress.
He says you lack creativity.
He says that you are too weak
to bear the massive power of the ring.
Well, that's because he's old.
And he's tired. And his time is up.
He's not worthy of
the "massive power" of the ring.
He didn't do shit to earn it.
And every time he looks at me,
he realizes that I'll do this better
than he's ever done it before
because I've worked
my entire fucking life for it.
The ring's always been mine.
That asshole's just keeping it warm.
Then go and get it.
John Stewart.
- You all right?
- Hey, listen.
I know you're probably
planning on just flying in
with your big green fist
and smashing shit
until you get to the weenie,
and I don't want to tell you
how to do your job.
- Well, then don't.
- But each of those guard towers
are going to be manned
with three sharpshooters,
and it will be your head next time.
So, I suggest
you tunnel in from underground.
Well, how do you propose I do that?
Did you draw this just now?
Yeah, I'm creative.
Let's go.
Here. You manifest it.
What?
We'll call it today's lesson.
Go ahead.
Let's dig.
Yeah.
"Five degrees to the left."
- How do you know all this?
- Did some research online.
I don't buy it. You're a Marine sniper.
Yeah, and after I was a Marine sniper,
I went to art school.
- Who the fuck are you?
- Trying to concentrate.
Well, you should be able to concentrate
and take personal questions
at the same time.
- Right.
- How's your mom?
She's great. How's your mom?
Dead. Cancer.
Jesus.
- Both your parents?
- Concentrate, will you?
It makes it easier. No ties.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
My mom had a good life, and my dad, he...
died the way he wanted to, a hero.
What was he like?
Fearless.
At least, that's what
he wanted people to think.
What was he afraid of?
We're here.
No benefactor, but what the fuck?
These weapons are too high-tech
to be from around here.
We were right.
- Benefactor's the Manhunter.
- Yeah.
Give me my ring.
I just heard a click.
Did you just hear a click?
Yeah. I just heard a click.
Don't move.
It's a pressure alarm.
If you move, it'll set it off.
- A good movie.
- Great movie.
So, we just make it believe
that I'm still standing on it.
Yeah, okay. How much do you weigh?
One-eighty-five. Ish.
Okay.
Okay, we're gonna
do this at the same time.
Three.
Two.
One.
I did say ish.
Fuck! I can't see!
Do something, Junior!
For Christ's sake, use the ring!
It's not fucking working!
Yes, sir. Two hundred a head.
Tonight.
My wife tells me you're an artist.
Yeah, she's right.
Are you talented?
Draw me.
What's your medium?
Charcoal.
Some good stock.
Hey, I've seen some shit,
even been to a planet
with sentient tentacles,
- but this is weird, right?
- Yeah.
You better get to doodling, Junior.
Hit me.
Take a seat. Relax your hands.
Hold it there. Thank you.
Zoe, honey, why don't you stay?
Okay.
You can holster up, partner.
Junior here, he can draw from memory.
Is that right?
Well, then you could probably
draw my wife.
Can we talk
about the elephant in the room?
- Which elephant?
- Not that one.
What goes on in this ranch?
Your guys, they shot darkness at us.
Now, call me paranoid,
but those guns seem tailor-made
for disabling Green Lanterns.
Hey, I told you.
We're ready for any kind of invasion.
Well, that's kind of worrisome, isn't it?
Well, it should only be worrisome
if the Lanterns pose a threat to my boss.
So now he's your boss?
I thought he was just the benefactor.
Don't get caught up in semantics.
Boss, benefactor...
- How about savior?
- Sure.
He did cure my cancer.
That's how we met. Zoe was my nurse.
Kept me alive
after the doctor said I was a goner.
Then he came,
worked his magic, and voilà.
- "His magic"?
- So to speak.
- Can you relax your shoulders?
- Now you talk about him like he's a god.
- I do, don't I?
- Hey, please.
Could you just stay still?
Everything changed when he showed up.
Crops grow. Kids thrive.
And you saw the hospital.
No one gets sick.
He takes care of us
in exchange for our protection.
So why don't you leave
so we can protect him?
Well, that's not gonna happen.
Well, that's unfortunate.
How about we skip the bluff
where you threaten to kill me
with a darkness gun?
'Cause we both know if I end up dead,
there's gonna be 100 Lanterns
at your front door,
and you're not even gonna
have time to hide my body.
You're right.
Killing a Lantern
would trigger a large response.
He's not a Lantern.
Dad, please put your dick away.
- Can I help you, Sheriff?
- I got a call about trespassers.
- Gonna assume it was these two.
- You're making a mistake, Kerry.
Just turn around and leave us be.
- That's not gonna happen.
- That's exactly what I said.
Let's go. I'm taking you in.
Move.
You had one shot
to get the guy and you whiffed.
If Zoe hadn't called me,
you'd be beyond fucked.
I live in beyond fucked.
Jesus, what is that, a catchphrase?
Do you hear yourself?
I'm in this shit with you now.
I broke into Billy's files.
I am this close
to finding your stupid benefactor.
Until I do, you're gonna lock your doors
and you're gonna wait
for me to tell you what happens next.
Is that clear?
Yes. Yes.
Superheroes don't really
lock their doors--
- Say yes!
- Yes.
Good.
You're free to go.
You kinda gotta let us out.
Oh my God.
Wait.
Sheriff, not even a date first?
Do you ever shut up?
Stewart, come here.
Macon let you just walk off his ranch.
He's not done with you two yet.
He knows where you are.
He'll send someone.
I'd take you into protective custody,
but we're still trying
to put the station back together, so...
Yeah, thank you.
Nothing for me?
You're a superhero.
Hey, Junior.
What?
We found Macon's weenie.
Why are you calling me on your cell?
Get to the payphone.
I talked to them already, Mama.
What did they say?
They're not gonna give me the ring.
They're making me take it from him.
Then take it.
Don't tell me you fell for that man.
Oh, come on.
He is a charming motherfucker.
I know exactly what the fuck he is.
Good. Don't lose focus.
I won't.
Mama, I gotta go.
Want to put that thing away?
What are you doing here?
Did Macon send you?
No. I came on my own.
Then why are you here?
I was thinking
how much better that is not in my truck.
This has to be the last time.
Okay.
Is there a reason why?
Well, your choices
are pretty much leave town or get killed.
I really hope you choose the former.
I'm sorry.
Why are you staying?
Because I feel
like everybody's lying to me.
Why?
Because that's exactly what I'm doing.
You think Jordan is lying to you?
Yeah.
Do you think I am?
When I tell you what I know...
everything changes.
I can't do that.
Because of your husband?
What do you owe him?
You read this all wrong. I don't owe him.
He owes me.
He was dying
when I met him and I saved his life.
And now...
I am trying to save yours.
Is that a yes?
You'll leave town?
Not a chance.
Damn.
Where'd it come from?
- Forty-five degrees northeast.
- Just fucking point!
Who the hell makes a satellite like this?
I've narrowed it down to Atlas,
Vermond, and Rutger.
Macon signed NDAs
with all three companies.
When?
All three were over ten years ago.
Atlas and Rutger, around 30.
It's gotta be one of them then.
Junior, you almost done?
Yeah, good. Almost done.
She was his grandmother.
What am I supposed to tell Noah?
Just tell him we're gonna
find out whoever did this.
Every satellite's registered
with the government.
Can you run that?
I can run the serial number
through the FCC database.
It's registered to Atlas, Inc.
Owner of Atlas, Inc. is Hector Hammond.
Runs a string of high-tech slaughterhouses
across the country.
No record of him anywhere before 1986.
Where's his nearest slaughterhouse?
Ninety-five miles away.
That's where he's gonna be then.
I'd bet Junior's life on it.
- What do you say?
- I think it seems too easy.
Elaborate.
You're the space cop.
Where's the investigation?
You think we just cracked
the case in this motel room?
Go on.
Well, he's got all these satellites
that can kill us all at any time.
But we're still alive.
And why did he choose
to kill Zoe and not us?
Because killing Zoe
was more than just a threat.
It was an invitation.
Jesus, Junior. That's not bad. Nice work.
Thanks.
Hey, Earth to Stewart.
Earth to Stewart.
How you doing?
What?
You have never asked me that before.
Your girlfriend blew up in front of you.
I'm handling it.
Kinda look like
you're shutting down your feelings.
It's part of the job.
People dying is part of the job.
You want some advice?
Avoid real relationships from here on out.
Keep people at a distance
for their own safety.
It's a lonely fucking job.
You ever talk with the other Lanterns?
I'm the only human. They're aliens.
One of them's a fucking squirrel.
- Nobody like me.
- I'm like you. I'm human.
That you are.
Yet you hate having me as a backup.
I do.
What's the plan?
I say...
we walk straight into his trap.
You wanna hear my idea?
I say you give me the ring.
Okay, Hammond's gonna
expect you to have it,
not me, element of surprise.
- So I'm a decoy.
- Yeah, you would be.
Oh, this isn't a training exercise.
You're good, but you're no me.
Maybe next time.
Hey.
I like the confidence, though.
Remember, security.
The first step towards
a safer environment.
Stay secure, stay vigilant.
Remember, security.
The first step
towards a safer environment.
Stay secure, stay vigilant.
Hey, where's Hammond?
I'm about done
with these weird-ass people.
Agreed.
Jazz, that can't be good.
Well, we found the cows.
That's why I'm vegan.
Mr. Hammond, I assume.
3248 Aspen Way.
- How's that?
- That's my parents' address.
I've already shown you
what my satellites are capable of.
In exactly three minutes
one of them
will obliterate your childhood home,
unless I enter a code onto this laptop.
You kill me, you kill them.
Yeah, that's great.
Dead man's trigger.
Don't act like you invented it.
Look, you invited us here.
Let's get down to business, huh?
You can save them, John.
Would you like to know how?
Don't talk to him. You talk to me.
You were approached
by a group of individuals
searching for me.
They gave you a phone. Call them.
Tell them you found me right here.
All right, so you can use
the old, uh, cow laser on them.
All right, that... that's clever.
Quick question.
How do you know about John's phone?
Is he always like this?
It must be insufferable.
You're gonna suffer
if you don't start talking to me.
- I'm the one with the ring.
- For now.
What does that mean?
When you checked into the motel,
I decided it best to listen in.
I've been monitoring
your conversations there.
Most of them were boring.
Most.
That's because he's old.
And he's tired. And his time is up.
He's not worthy
of the "massive power" of the ring.
He didn't do shit to earn it.
And every time he looks at me,
he realizes that I'll do this better
than he's ever done it before
because I've worked
my entire fucking life for it.
The ring's always been mine.
That asshole's just keeping it warm.
Then go and get it.
You're obsolete, Mr. Jordan.
Replaced by a new
and vastly improved model.
That must be terrifying.
- What color is Abin Sur?
- What?
The fellow who gave me this ring,
who dropped you off
on this planet before he died?
You're the Manhunter. What color was he?
- I don't remember.
- He was a very memorable shade.
I've met a lot of aliens.
I don't think you have.
I think you're bullshit.
I think you're a smokescreen
for someone else. A decoy.
One minute and counting.
You know, an old friend of mine
recently told me
something about Manhunters.
Very good at replicating other organisms,
nearly perfect.
But when it comes
to copying carbon-based life forms,
the only organ
you can't get just right is the heart.
It's an undetectable flaw,
when you're alive.
But once your heart stops,
it crystallizes.
So the only way
to prove that you're a Manhunter
is to rip your fucking heart out.
You kill me, his parents die.
I got no problem with that.
I mean, I would have given
a shit before the recording,
but now I'm starting to think, you know,
a hero's journey, it should really
only start after the parents are dead.
- The fuck are you doing?
- You kill Stewart's family,
I got no reason to keep you alive.
So you got
about ten seconds to tell me the truth.
- Hal.
- Nine.
- Eight.
- Stop.
- Seven.
- Stop!
- Six.
I'm human! I'm human!
Fucking put in that code right now.
- They're safe.
- What if you were fucking wrong?
I'm never wrong.
Okay.
Okay, who are you?
- Who the fuck are you? Speak up!
- I'm Hector Gutierrez.
I was an engineering student.
He came to me,
offering me incredible technology,
said I could use it to help my family,
- my community.
- Who the fuck is the Manhunter?
Isn't it obvious?
Will Macon.
I was gonna give it back.
What?
At Macon's ranch, I was wearing the ring.
All I needed to do was say the oath.
But I didn't.
And when I asked for it again,
I just wanted to show you
what I was capable of.
I believe you.
- It's all good.
- Really?
Honestly, I'd have done the same thing.
And what you said wasn't all untrue.
I didn't do much to earn this thing.
And there's a very good chance
that you might end up being better.
I can be a bit of an asshole at times.
You know, the Guardian
said you broke a vow.
You believe everything they say.
You ought to give that a rest.
I mean, look what they're doing to me now.
But that said, I did break a vow.
Went to see Sinestro.
So he told you about the crystal heart?
Among other things.
They're ruthless, Junior.
They assimilate into communities
by attaching to weak spots.
It's what they're programmed to do.
So what you're saying
is they have no other choice?
They find a path to power every time,
and if they identify
a threat to that power,
they'll manipulate that threat
into believing anything they want them to.
Remind you of anyone we know?
Yeah, it must be Macon.
Like Hector said.
Yeah.
Call that alien hit squad.
Tell them to meet us at the cafe.
Nah, they don't trust you.
Why don't you tell them
to meet you at the cafe, then?
They trust you.
Yeah.
- Yeah?
- I've got who we're looking for.
That's good.
Meet me at the cafe
just outside of Rushville.
We're close.
Yeah.
What?
I really did forgive you.
Thought you'd be honest.
About what?
When Zoe blew up,
I didn't get why you weren't upset.
I thought you were made of stone.
I wondered why you weren't sad.
I knew you liked her.
Now, with Hector,
when you freaked out
about your parents, and...
it kinda all hit me.
You ain't made of stone, Junior.
You aren't upset
because you know Zoe isn't dead.
And I don't know how she managed
to get out of that car alive
unless she's a Manhunter.
The thing that I can't figure out
is how long you've known.
I didn't know. I just had a feeling.
Fuck feeling, that's your gut, Junior.
- Yeah.
- Well, bravo.
Congratulations, truly.
The student surpasses the teacher.
I wasn't trying to keep anything from you.
I just didn't know for certain,
so I didn't want to say anything.
Oh, you haven't told the Guardians?
I haven't told the Guardians
anything we've been doing
because you asked me not to.
- Right?
- Except that I'm old and tired.
Well, I'm sorry about that.
I'm sorry about the rental.